so now that we know what ilp is let's
look at an example of computing the lp
just so that we can be on the same page
about that first we need a program
so let's say we have this program we
have already renamed it so that only the
true dependencies remain so now let's
look for those true dependencies
we write to p10
this instruction doesn't use p10
actually the first one that uses p10 is
this one
we write to p6 nothing uses p6
we write to p5
this one uses p5 so there is a
dependence basically here
and another one here
and then here we produce p4 so we only
have really these two true dependencies
so now let's look at like what can
execute in which cycle to do that the
best way is to just kind of check off
instructions and counter cycles so in
the first cycle we can do this
this this
and this because none of these
instructions has any incoming
dependencies yet in the second cycle
okay this one cannot be done in the
first cycle because it has a dependence
from this and this and that's not been
done in the first cycle yet so after the
first cycle all of these are done so now
we can do this so what we have what we
get is now the ilp
is equal to how many instructions
five
over how many cycles two we got an ilp
of 2.5 again we didn't need to know what
the processor looks like
now some convenient tricks for computing
the lp first
i didn't actually need to rename the
program if this program had real
registers with some anti and output
dependencies
i could just fake renaming but just
looking at where the true dependencies
are and completely ignoring the anti and
output dependencies why well because the
renaming would eliminate them anyway all
that would be left is the true
dependencies so you actually when you're
computing the lp don't really need to
look at a rename program you can do it
directly on the program as it was
written you just need to follow only the
true dependencies and completely ignore
the the antenna output dependencies
second you know when checking this off
be mindful to kind of remember how many
cycles you're computing and also what
has been done and so on and then you
know just be careful also to kind of
divide the right thing with the right
thing so it's five instructions over two
cycles not the other way around